# **Thomas Scarlett**

70 Warriewood Rd, Warriewood NSW, Australia, 2102 Phone:(02)99993989 Mobile: 0406128107 Email: tscarlett@live.com.au

#### **Personal Profile**

I'm a highly personable adult with demonstrated strengths of academic achievement, and a proven ability to work well in either a team or alone. I have experience working in a variety of environments, both indoors and outdoors, which has exhibited my strong work ethic, and an ability to adapt to new work places. I love travelling and learning about people, different cultures and the natural world. I have a strong sense of adventure and enjoy trying new things. I have a deep appreciation and good knowledge of the natural world. I have experience in various outdoor roles from regenerating bushland to building walking tracks and boardwalks.

## **Demonstrated strengths**

- Capability to work in both a team and individual environment with or without supervision.
- Great communication skills dealing with colleagues, customers and all levels of management.
- Physically fit, hard working and able to stay focused.
- Proven to take initiative and learn new tasks with relative ease.
- Working outdoors and in various weather conditions
- Working with and around various types of machinery

## **Skills and Experience**

- General Bush track construction and maintenance skills, including concreting, footings and retaining wall construction.
- Identification of native plants and invasive weeds in the Sydney region
- Various weeding techniques, e.g. hand pull/dig, crown cut, stem scrape, cut and paint, and knapsack spraying.
- Planting and transplanting.
- Use of various construction and gardening tools.
- Working around machinery.
- Experienced bar attendant, bistro attendant, tray service, till operator, cash handler, serving
  meals, clearing tables, poker machine attendant, change bar attendant, Keno and TAB
  operator and experienced at preparing for functions.
- Ability to operate in a culturally diverse and changing environment.
- Strong work ethic and a loyal employee.
- Logically minded with aptitude for problem solving.
- Cleaning, maintaining and sanitizing equipment and workspace.
- Working with chemicals.
- Following WHS procedures and undertaking risk assessments.
- Working with and around food and carrying out safety and hygienic requirements.
- Polite and professional customer service.
- Training new staff

## **Employment History**

Oct 2021-date Position: Track Worker

Company: Track and Trail Management Services

Contact: Thomas Schmidt, 0409029656

Skills: digging holes and benching slopes, pre-fabricating FRP tressils, preparing conduit and string line for the position and gradient of the track, cutting panels to create a flush walking platform, training new staff, p articipating in OH&S, dressing rock, using various specialty tools, using leverage to move heavy objects.

Oct 2019-June 2021 Position: Bush Regenerator

Company: Waratah Eco Works

Contact: James Donnelly, 0411268190

Skills: Weeding, Planting, mulching, habitat creation, Plant identification, Watering, and Seed

collection.

Sep 2018-Feb 2019 Position: All-rounder

Company: Eucla motor motel and caravan park

Contact: Paul Retsas, 0408715693

Skills: gardener, kitchen hand/cook, barista, housekeeping, reception, bartending, waiter, and

Service station attendant.

Apr-2018-Jul 2019 Position: Kitchen hand

Company: Kings Canyon Resort Contact: Ben Laurie, 0438401542

Skills: cleaning and storing dishes, maintaining dishwasher, sanitising workstations, maintaining

cleaning chemical inventory, assisting in food preparation, plating deserts.

Aug 2016-Dec 2017 Position: Bush Regenerator/Track Construction

Company: Toolijooa Location: Terry Hills, NSW

Contact: Ryan Mandell, 0410529859

Skills: weeding, planting and transplanting, plant identification, stone track construction,

box-step construction, working around machinery, jute matting.

March 2016-Aug 2016 Position: Bush Regenerator/Track Construction

Company: Green Army/Manpower

Location: Ku-Ring-Gai Chase National Park, NSW

Contact: Wayne Davis, 0429960378

Skills: Weeding, planting, transplanting, plant identification, track maintenance and construction.

Nov 2015-Sept 2016 Position: Casual Bartender

Company: The Master Builders Club Location: Dee Why, NSW, Australia Contact: Matt Hacck 99711688

Skills: bar work, cleaning, cash handling, serving meals to tables, clearing tables, Keno, TAB, Poker

machine attendant.

From January to May, 2013, I travelled throughout SE Asia. While in Thailand I volunteered with Elephant stay, where I worked directly with the elephants and learnt about them.

July 2012-Jan 2013 Position: Full time Kitchen hand

Company: Sweet Sensation

Location: Brookvale, NSW, Australia Contact: Gavin Towers, 0410526658

Skills: Food preparation, baking, cleaning.

June 2012-Jan 2013 Position: Casual Bartender

Company: The Master Builders Club Location: Dee Why, NSW, Australia Contact: Matt Hacck, 99711688

Skills: Bar work, cleaning, cash handling, Keno, TAB, Poker machine attendant.

From July to December of 2011 I travelled throughout Western Europe.

Dec 2010-June 2011 Position: Casual Bartender/Customer Service Attendant

Company: Pittwater RSL Club Location: Mona Vale, NSW, Australia Contact: Shay O'Connor, (02)9997 3833

Skills: Bar work, Cleaning, tray service, cash handling, Keno, and TAB.

In late 2009 I spent 2 months traveling in Laos and Thailand. I did volunteer work with the Mirror foundation teaching children English and mending roads in Chiang Rai, Thailand.

### **Education**

July-Dec 2019 Certificate III in Conservation and Land Management

Ryde TAFE, NSW

July 2013-Nov 2015 Studied Wilderness and Environmental Studies

University of Tasmania, Hobart Campus

Jan 2005-Nov 2011 Year 12 Higher School Certificate

Pittwater High School, Mona Vale, NSW, Australia

#### **Certificates and Awards**

- (RSA) Responsible Service of Alcohol
- (RCG) Responsible Conduct of Gambling
- Chemical certificate
- First aid certificate
- White card
- 4WD certificate